# **DO VUONG PHUC**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(+84) 707 953 475

**■** 16th Oct, 2001

• HCM City, Ward 16, District 8

in phuc16102001

phuc16102001

k phuc16102001

<u>≥ phuc16102001</u>

#### **ABOUT ME**

A backend engineer with 3 YoE in software engineer field. I am goal-oriented, dedicated to my work, and always open to new experiences, especially those related to my field of study, to enhance my coding practice.

I have gained many from being a leader of group projects, which is why problem-solving, presentation and leadership skills are not weaknesses of mine. I have a strong passion for software engineering and computer science.

#### **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

#### University of Science (HCMUS)

Artificial Intelligent major | 2019 - 2023

- Bachelor in Information Technology (GPA: 3.94/4)
- Graduated valedictorian (Top 1)

### **LANGUAGE**

English: IELTS Academic Certificate 6.5 (B2 level)

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Valedictorian graduated with the highest GPA
- Top-rated lancer with job success rate of 100%
- Scholarship for the excellent student each semester
- Step STEM Alive Singapore 4th Runner-up prize
- Excellent Students in Informatics Contest 3rd prize
- 30/4 Olympic contest 2018 Gold medal
- 30/4 Olympic contest 2017 Gold medal

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming language**

• Java, Python, Rust, JavaScript, C++

#### Software engineering

- Spring, Jenkins, SonarQube, Grafana
- Docker, Helm chart, Kubernetes (K8S), Nginx
- MSSQL, MySQL, Postgre, MongoDB
- GitHub, CI/CD, Swagger, Jira, Trello

#### Distributed system

- Elastic search (ELK), Kafka, Redis
- · ZooKeeper, HDFS, Airflow, Spark, Hive

#### **Machine learning**

- WEKA, KNIME, Tableau, PowerBI, Sk-learn
- PySpark, PyTorch, TensorFlow

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Backend Engineer**

Naver Vietnam | Korean market | March 2023 - Present

- Design and develop large-scale zero-downtime systems using Java Spring & distributed systems on Naver cloud.
- Responsible with DevOps task (e.g. build CI/CD pipeline).
- Build SLI charts & do monitoring the system.

#### Freelance Software/Data Engineer

<u>Upwork</u> | International market | November 2022 - March 2023

• Develop tools and utilities (e.g. syntax checker, trading probabilistic calculator), analyze data, and build machine learning models.

#### **Blockchain Developer Intern**

VBPO JSC | Vietnam market | May 2022 - Oct 2022

Research blockchain technologies and develop a blockchain-based application for real estate. Full-stack development using NEAR and Aurora Engine.

## **SOFTWARE PROJECTS**

#### <u>Naver Blog (블로그)</u>

- Blog on map
  - Design & implement the map feature for the Naver Blog service, which display over 184M user's blogs on Naver Map and Google map.
  - o Migrate data from a source-of-truth using Kafka which can serve up-to 1000 message per second.
  - Optimized the maximum page-fetch latency from 30 seconds to 0.3 seconds for a page with 65.000+ map locations.
- Blog RSS
  - Implement RSS feed feature to provide top 50 latest posts of a user.
  - o Leveraging Vitess database to provide a more highavailability system and sharding 4TB data of posts.
- Techstack: Spring boot, K8S, ELK, Kafka, Redis, Nginx, SonarQube, Zookeeper, Vitess, CQRS pattern.

#### Naver BBoom (뿜)

- Maintain a social network service for more than 6M **users** to shares humor and meme posts.
- Migrate system from Server-side rendering (SSR) to Client-side rendering (CSR) without downtime.
- · Optimized many features of the legacy system (e.g. search feature, favorite post feature).
- Tech stack: Spring boot, Spring integration, K8S, ELK, Redis, Slave-master MySQL, Nginx, Jenkins, HDFS, SonarQube, Zookeeper.

## MACHINE LEARNING PROJECTS

#### **Deep Q-learning Snake**

- Develop Snake game as an environment to train the DQN model and integrate it with the A\* algorithm.
- Achieve the **1st prize** in a university contest which to find the solution for Snake game.
- GitHub: DQN Snake repository

#### Dog and cat classification and detection

- Leverage the CNN model and transfer learning to classify, detect cats, and dogs in an image.
- Kaggle: <u>Kaggle notebooks</u>GitHub: <u>GitHub repository</u>

#### **WORKING REFERENCES**

#### Mr. Le Ngoc Hieu

Team leader Email: ngochieubmt@gmail.com Phone: (+84) 907 769 634

#### Mr. Tran Cong Thuc

Backend engineer Email: thucctin@gmail.com Phone: (+84) 976 335 341

#### **PUBLICATION**

# Unifying Global and Local Scene Entities Modelling for Precise Action Spotting

- Propose a method to improve current action spotting vision models by unifying global and local feature.
- The method not only help Al model improving the accuracy but also more explainable
- By applying the GLIP a zero-shot learning model of Google, the method can apply on arbitrary sports.
- Publisher: WCCI IJCNN 2024
- Presentation: Yokohama 30 June
- **GitHub**: <u>Github repository</u>

#### Product recommendation for Huimitu ecommerce using Association Rule with KNIME

- Story about how I built a recommendation system for an e-commerce (named Huimitu) system, using KNIME.
- Publisher: Medium Low Code for Data Science